Mateo Gregory

Systems Engineer & Computer Science Full-Stack Engineer Project Manager Mail: magremenez@gmail.com

Linkedin: Marthox Website: Marthox.com Phone: (+57) 316 4193085

MSc Engineering Student at Universidad del Valle, graduate as System Engineer from Universidad del Valle, proficient in English (B2 certified), with knowledge and experience mainly in Python and JavaScript and some experience in Java, C#, Ruby and Elixir. I have experience in frameworks and libraries such as React, NodeJS, Django, Flask, Fast-Api, Phoenix, Svelte and Rails. Version control (Git) and remote version control hosting platforms (GitHub).

Experience

Full-Stach Engineer at Inchcape (October 2023 - Now)

- Contribute to over ten websites in over five countries by mantaining, developing new features, fixing existing bugs and refactoring the codebase, leading to opening new markets expecting to increase the company's revenue.
- Improve the user experience of the websites by developing features specific for each country, and by following user-centered design principles, increasing the user engagement and the conversion rate.

Skills and tools: C# (C-Sharp), JavaScript, Html, Css, .Net, Umbraco, Atlassian, Jira, Git, Agile Software Development, Project Management.

Backend Engineer at Reserve (July 2022 - May 2023)

- Optimize, refactor and create over ten API endpoints, by implementing new features and fixing existing bugs, improving the stability of the application up to 99.98%.
- Open the door to the Mexican market by integrating a third-party remittances provider, allowing users to withdraw and deposit money using cash, reaching to a market of \$58.5 billion.
- Improve the robustness of the application in different workload scenarios, by implementing a customizable load testing tool, allowing the team to identify bottlenecks and improve the performance of the application.

Skills and tools: Python, JavaScript, Html, Css, FastAPI, React, Full-Stack Backend Development, RESTful API Development, API Integrations, Git, Agile Software Development, Project Management.

Full-Stack Engineer at Kommit (October 2021 - July 2022)

- Improve stability and functionality of Podnation by implementing new features and fixing existing bugs, mantaining the already high aplication uptime of 99.99%.
- Release a new feature for Podnation allowing users to create and share clips of their favorite podcasts, increasing the user engagement and the conversion rate by 10%.
- Refactor and enhance a U.S. Military Foundation's hardware device driver, significantly aiding speech-impaired Parkinson's patients, achieving 99.99% improvement in application robustness and stability.

Skills and tools: JavaScript, Elixir, Ruby, React, AdonisJs, ElectronJs, Phoenix, Ruby on Rails, Full-Stack Development, Git, Agile Software Development, Project Management.

Freelance Full-Stack Engineer (January 2021 - August 2021)

- Develop a patient-specific, teeth-like interface, demographically optimized for the target audience, by implementing a custom React component library, increasing user engagement by 15%.
- Craft intuitive user interfaces, optimized for the target audience demographic to enhance user experience and engagement, by implementing a custom React component, increasing user engagement by 15%.
- Built a role-based database model for efficient management of patient, doctor, and appointment data assuring data integrity and security.
- Oversaw deployment, setup, and configuration of the application on Digital Ocean servers using Docker, ensuring a smooth and efficient deployment process.

Skills: JavaScript, Python, SQL, React, Flask, PostgreSQL, Docker, Digital Ocean, Freelance Development, Full-Stack Development, Project Management, Git, Agile Software Development, RESTful API Development.

Soft Skills

Autonomy, Teamwork, Goal-Oriented, Leadership, Conflict Management, Teaching Skills, Active Listening, Clear Communication, Problem-Solving, Flexibility, Creative Thinking, Time Management, Attention to Detail, User-Centric Approach, Analytical Skills, Emotional Intelligence, Project Management, Persistence.

Education

Degree of Systems Engineering at Universidad del valle Master in Systems Engineer at Universidad del valle $(June\ 2016 - December\ 2021)$ $(January\ 2023 - Now)$

Academic Experience

Complexity and optimization

- SAT Reductor
- Electric Station

Image processing

- Image processing
- MIA

Software development

- UV energy
- Nova

Artificial Intelligence

- Hex Agent
- Sokoban Agents

Networking

- GNS3 topology

Virtualization

- Vitual Box Rest API

Extras

- Universidad del valle academic accompaniment monitor
- Universidad del valle custom accompaniment monitor
- Attendant to "Pioneras-Dev" gamification workshop by Edwin Gamboa
- Work on writing an academic paper with Valeria Rivera, Emily Carvajal, and Jose Bernal
- Assistant to the 13th Colombian Congress of computing